Guide to the Rufus James Trimble Papers TAM.550
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Rufus James Trimble Papers
1885-1954
1910-1920
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Trimble, Rufus James, 1888-1974
TAM.550
0.5 Linear Feet (1 box)
Rufus James Trimble (1888-1974), was a socialist, a lawyer (Columbia Law School), and the nephew of Rufus Weeks, a financial supporter of The Masses.The collection contains correspondence, including his reports from a 1911 trip to Europe to investigate the socialist movement there, for which he carried a letter of introduction from Morris Hillquit to Camill Huysmans, of the Maison du Peuple in Brussels, or which he wrote a report, correspondence with his relative Rufus Weeks, general correspondence, general correspondence, photographs from Trimble's European trip, a manuscript on cooperation, notes, clippings, checkbooks, a book, the Genealogy of the Family of George Weekes (1886), and a membership book (1898) for the Societe Cooperative des Sabotiers due Cerfontaine.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials found in collection, provenance is unknown but was likely donated by Joan Weeks Trimble Smith and Verna Rudd Kenvin in circa 1986. The accession number associated with this collection is 2010.067.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Historical/Biographical Note
Rufus James Trimble (1888-1974), was a socialist, a lawyer (Columbia Law School), and the nephew of Rufus Weeks, a financial supporter of The Masses.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains correspondence, including Trimble's reports from a 1911 trip to Europe to investigate the socialist movement there, for which he carried a letter of introduction from Morris Hillquit to Camille Huysmans, of the Maison du Peuple in Brussels, or which he wrote a report, correspondence with his relative Rufus Weeks, general correspondence, general correspondence, photographs from his European trip, a manuscript on cooperation, notes, clippings, checkbooks, a book, the Genealogy of the Family of George Weekes (1886), and a membership book (1898) for the Societe Cooperative des Sabotiers due Cerfontaine.
Cooperation |z United States.; Socialists -- United States.; Socialism |z Europe.; Weeks, Rufus; Trimble, Rufus James, 1888-1974; Maison du Peuple (Brussels, Belgium); Hillquit, Morris, 1869-1933
- Papers (Box 1)
  - Checkbook: Lucy R. Trimble, 1909 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Checkbook: Rufus James Trimble, 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Clippings, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Co-Operation [chapter length manuscript], undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence: European Trip(s), 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, 1910-1914, 1950, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Rufus Weeks [uncle?], 1910-1911 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Genealogy of the Family of George Weekes, 1885 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Huxley on Education: Address by H.F. Osborn; Notes by RJW, Sep 28, 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Photographs (of demonstrations) and postcard: Europe, circa 1911 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Societe Cooperative des Sabotiers de Cerfontaine: Membership Book, 1898 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Untitled manuscript [A Report on the Maison du Peuple), circa 1911 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Stern, Meta "Why Women Need the Vote: Address at the 42nd Annual Convention of the National American Woman Suffrage Association, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)